Guide to the Bill Dixon Papers MSS.481
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Music, 1936, 1941, 1959-2012; 125.72 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 39 flat boxes, 17 tall LP boxes, 24 manuscript boxes, 5 oversize flat boxes, 1 rolled storage box, and 2 flat-file folders.; 402.54 Gigabytes in 1,214 digital files.
  - Subseries I.A: Commercial and Studio Recordings, 1960-2012; 45 Linear Feet in 23 flat boxes, 16 record cartons, 3 LP boxes, 1 manuscript box, and 1 cassette box
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36746
      This disc includes: 1 - Voices 2 - Footwork 3 - Summerdance 4 - Shrike 5 - Velvet 6 - Silver Point 7 - Suri-Mono 8 - Moment - 9 - London
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36747
      This disc includes "Silences For," "Sisyphus," "Relay (Odyssey)," Bill Dixon in Italy (Firenze), "Papyrus," "Voices," Bill Dixon and Leslie Winston, Arrizzi, Norid
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36748
      This disc includes: 1. "Metamorphosis," 2. "Letters: Suspects," 3. Orch Piece '72, 4. "Sequences" '72, 5. "Shrike" '73, 6. "Var. Night and Day" '79, 7. [illegible] '73,
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36749
      This disc includes "Papyrus" Volumes I and II, "Silver Point," "Essay," and "Ritual"
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36750
      This disc includes Albahari, Friedman, Wesleyan Solo
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36751
      This disc includes Albahari, Friedman, Moore, Fahlin, Wesleyan, Grossman
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36752
      This disc includes Albahari, J. Moore, Marie Fahlin, Wesleyan Solo
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36753
      This disc includes "Webern," "Shrike"
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36754
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36755
      This disc includes Albahari, Friedman, Danspace, Jack Moore, and Marie Fahlin
    - Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36756
    - Compilation Disc -- "10 Examples Solo", Undated; cuid36743
    - Compilation Disc -- "For Andrew Lindstrom", Undated; cuid36757
      This disc includes "Intents and Purposes" and three Bill Dixon / Tony Widoff duets performed in Hudson, New York and at Bennington College.
    - Compilation of Piano Performances, Undated; cuid36758
      This disc includes "Relay," "Firenze," "Silence," and other piano recordings
    - Compilation of Trumpet and Bass Performances Featuring Chris Faris, Undated; cuid36759
    - Compilation Tape, Undated; cuid36768 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2046)
      This is a handmade cassette published by Bill Dixon, Inc. and Metamorphosis Music, BMI. This tape contains music excerpts, including "Dusty Rose," "Waltz for Jack Moore," Dance Pieces, Untitled Pieces
    - Compilation Tape, Undated; cuid36771 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2490)
      This tape contains "Dominos," "Shrike," "Velvet," "Sori-nomo," Louise Wade, and the Stone Performance.
    - Compilation Tape, Undated; cuid36763 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1556)
      This tape contains "Pages," "Sequence," "Places and Things," "Orchestra Piece," and "Webern."
    - Compilation Tape -- Bill Dixon Compositions, Undated; cuid36766 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1997)
    - Compilation Tape -- FORE recordings, Duet with Drummer, Undated; cuid36767 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1951)
    - Compilation Tape -- "Mostly Records", Undated; cuid36772 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2494)
    - Compilation Tape -- Music and Talk Excerpts, Undated; cuid36773 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_073)
    - Compilation Tape -- Recent Duets and Ensemble, Undated; cuid36769 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1953)
    - Compilation Tape -- "Solo Reel of Unknowns", Undated; cuid36764 (Box 40, Audiocassette 481_1952)
    - Compilation Tape -- Solo Trumpet, Undated; cuid36770 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1631)
    - Compilation Tape -- "Summer Song", Undated; cuid36765 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1603)
    - David Bindman and Bill Dixon Improvs, Undated; cuid36775 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_681)
    - Dum Praeliaretur, Maïkotron Unit, Undated; cuid36777
    - Ferrari Record, Undated; cuid36779 (Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1532)
    - The Forbidden Playground Film Soundtrack, Undated; cuid36722 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1354)
      Film by Maxine Halloff; Dance by Edith Stephen; Music by Bill Dixon
    - German Radio Broadcast -- Cecil Taylor, Undated; cuid36780
    - Graffiti Talk -- Janna Levenstein, Undated; cuid36781 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_673)
    - Implosion Film Score by Bob Pozar, Undated; cuid36760 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1463)
    - Lou Fischer Music Publishing, Inc. Sampler #12, Undated; cuid36782 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_650)
    - Music by Bill Dixon, Undated; cuid36783 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2043)
    - Music Sent to Dixon For Review, Undated; cuid36784 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_193)
    - Piano Compositions, Undated; cuid36786 (Box 20, Audiocassette 481_093)
    - Piece Submitted to Bill Dixon for Copywriting, Undated; cuid36463 (Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2335)
      The name the piece and the person who sent the tape to Dixon are not noted.
      Reel 481_2335 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - Pronto Ascolto by Bill Dixon and Tony Oxley, Undated; cuid36787
    - "Sequence" Complete Copy, Undated; cuid36788 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2476, Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2523)
    - Son of Sisyphus, Undated; cuid36789 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2033)
    - Son of Sisyphus, Thoughts, Undated; cuid36733 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2017)
    - Soul Note Record, Undated; cuid36790 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2030)
    - "Spanish Fly", Undated; cuid36791 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_679)
    - "Special Compilation", Undated; cuid36792
    - Streaming: Contemporary Improvisation at New England Conservatory, Undated; cuid36793 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_670)
    - Tchicai Group -- WBAI Demo, Undated; cuid8727 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1461)
      Featuring John Tchicai, Bill Dixon, Jimmy Sterenson, and Jonny Murray
    - Test Tape, Undated; cuid36721 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1466)
    - Trumpet and Piano Duets, Undated; cuid36778 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2048)
    - Unlabeled Recording Session, Undated; cuid36798
    - Unlabeled Recording Session, Undated; cuid36799
    - Unlabeled Recording Session, Undated; cuid36800
    - Video Compilation Disc, Undated; cuid36801
      This disc includes the films Wealth of a Nation, Index, and Lyon performance footage
    - Video Compilation Disc -- Material from DVDs, Undated; cuid36797 (Box 67, Vhs 481_1147)
      Duration: 122 minutes
    - Vis a vis, Undated; cuid36795 (Box 27, Audiocassette 481_662)
    - Waltz for Jack Moore, Undated; cuid36785 (Box 24, Audiocassette 481_589)
    - "Webern" for Andy -- Examples, Undated; cuid36802
  - Subseries I.B: Performance Recordings, 1960-2011; 75 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 25 flat boxes, 16 LP boxes, 1 manuscript box, and 1 cassette box
    This subseries includes recordings of Bill Dixon's musical performances and rehearsals, including solo performances as well as duets, trios, quartets, and sextets with musicians such as Stephen Horenstein, Cecil Taylor, Tony Widoff, Chris Faris, and Ron Stabinsky; choreographed collaborations with Judith Dunn; and large orchestral works. Notable performances include the Newport Jazz Festival (1966), the Autumn Festival in Paris (1976), the Judson Memorial Church Sessions (1964-1967), and the Vision Festival in New York City (2000, 2007). It also includes performance compilation tapes handmade by Bill Dixon.
    - Compilation Tape -- Solo Trumpet, Duets, Ensemble, circa 1960-1992; cuid36803 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2486)
    - Bill Dixon Trio at the Bitter End, New York City, July 9, 1961; cuid36807 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1961, Box 34, Audiocassette 481_1508)
      This cassette contains a live recording by Joe Di Carlo at the Bitter End Cafe, Bleeker St., NYC. It features Bill Dixon on trumpet, Dudley Watson on bass, and Joe D. Carlo on Drums.
    - Archie Shepp, Bill Dixon, Cecil Taylor, 1962; cuid36804
    - "Metamorphosis" Orchestra Works, 1962-1966; cuid36808
    - Archie Shepp and Bill Dixon, February 21, 1963; cuid36809 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1991)
      Duration: 31 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
    - Compilation Tape -- Italy, Volles, March, 1964; cuid36814 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2466)
    - "A Song for Children" at Judson Hall, December, 1964; cuid36815 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1376)
    - "Pomegranate #2" at Judson Memorial Church, "Serendipity" at Judson Hall, 1964, 1966; cuid36811 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2461)
      Duration: 41 minutes
    - "Song for Children," Rehearsal for "Voices," Solos, 1964-1966; cuid36812 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1972)
    - Bill Dixon Discussing Music, Performance Clips, circa 1969; cuid36813 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1390)
    - "Relay", circa 1970; cuid36820
      - Audio (Box 56, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1401, Box Shared Fales 106, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2093)
      - Video (Box 76, Betacam 481_2352)
    - Bill Dixon - Alan Silva Trio Performance, 1965; cuid8725 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_101)
    - Dixon Jazz Festival and Conversation with Jon Murray, 1965; cuid36819
      - Audio (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1482)
      - Papers (Box 213, Folder 20)
    - Bill Dixon and Jon Murray, March, 1965; cuid36821
    - Jazz Composer's Orchestra: "The Lovely People", April 10, 1965; cuid36822 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2451)
    - "Mirage for Brass Quintet and Duo," Columbia University McMillan Theatre, December 8, 1965; cuid36823 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1377)
    - "Anatomy of a Piece: Mirage for Brass Quintet," McMillan Theater, Madison, Wisconsin, 1965-1971; cuid36824 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1966)
    - Bill Dixon and Judith Dunn at Newport, Rhode Island, 1966; cuid36825 (Box 48, Dat 481_2710, Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1973)
    - "Metamorphosis" Rehearsal, Trumpet Solos, circa 1966; cuid36805 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1095, Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1347)
    - "Pomegranate" Performance at Newport, Rhode Island, 1966; cuid36827 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2009)
    - "Pomegranate," "Motorcycle," "Noveau Ne" Performance at Judson Memorial Church, 1966; cuid36828 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1569)
      Duration: 51 minutes
    - "Motorcycle" by Bill Dixon and Alan Silva -- Duet Clips, 1966; cuid36831 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1391)
    - Newport, 1966; cuid36834
    - Rehearsal for Newport Jazz Festival, June, 1966; cuid8717 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2063)
    - Rehearsal "Solos and Voices": Pozar (Drums) and Norris (Cello), 1966; cuid36833 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1352)
    - "Dew Horse," "Pomegranate," and "Motorcycle" at Judson Memorial Church, July, 1966
      - Audio, cuid36836 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1360)
      - Papers (Box 213, Folder 18)
    - "Nouveau Ne" and "Groundspeed" at Judson Memorial Church, July, 1966; cuid36835 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1460)
      Duration: 24 minutes
    - "Dew Horse" Performed at Judson Memorial Church, July 11, 1966; cuid8729 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1357)
      Featuring music by Bill Dixon and dance and choreography by Judith Dunn.
    - "Pomegranate" Performed at Judson Memorial Church, July 11, 1966; cuid8730 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1458, Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1363)
    - "Groundspeed" Performed at Judson Memorial Church, July 18, 1966; cuid8716 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1359)
    - "Nouveau Né" and "Motorcycle" Performed at Judson Memorial Church, July 18, 1966; cuid8711 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1358)
    - "Dew Horse" Performed at Judson Memorial Church, July 25, 1966; cuid8731 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1356)
    - "Metamorphosis" Performed at Judson Memorial Church, July 25, 1966; cuid8732 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1324, 481_1355)
    - "Intents and Purposes" Rehearsal, September 26, 1966; cuid36837 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1553)
    - "Metamorphosis" Rehearsal, September 26, 1966; cuid36838 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1371)
    - Bill Dixon and Judith Dunn Excerpts: Performance at Hunter College, New York; "Work Print"; Dance Theater Workshop, 1966-1967; cuid36826 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2471)
      Duration: 64 minutes
    - "Intents and Purposes" Performed by the Bill Dixon Orchestra in New York City, 1966-1967; cuid36839
    - Orchestra Works: "Metamorphosis," "Orch. Piece #1," "Orch. Piece #2," "Work for Orch," "This Is Our Strategy", 1966-1976; cuid36829 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1587)
    - Performance Excerpts: "Voices," Solos, "Workprint", 1966-1967; cuid36840 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1378)
    - Trumpet Solos, 1967-1968; cuid36842 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1370)
    - "Nightfall Piece" Rehearsal (Complete Reorchestrated Version), circa 1967-1968; cuid36843 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1345)
      Featuring Bill Dixon (trumpet), Jacques Coursil (trumpet), Frank DaMessio (trumpet)
    - Albert Ayler Quartet, Ornette Coleman Trio Performance, July 21, 1967; cuid36845
    - Intents and Purposes, 1967; cuid36841 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1568)
    - "Voices", January 17, 1967; cuid36844 (Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1346)
    - Trumpet Solos from Original GWU Reel, Summer, 1968; cuid36850 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2031)
    - "Nightfall Pieces" (Reorchestrated Version), 1968; cuid36852 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1375)
    - Compilation of Performances at Bennington College and Williams College, 1968-1969; cuid36853 (Box 41, Audiocassette 481_1965)
    - Solos, circa 1968-1969; cuid36851 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1565)
    - Compilation Tape -- Trumpet Solos, Albert Ayler Sequence, and Multitrack Solos for Dance at George Washington University, 1968-1974; cuid36854 (Box 44, Audiocassette 481_2500)
    - Judith Dunn and Bill Dixon Performance, Carriage Barn, December 11, 1969; cuid36861
      - Video -- 1 of 2, cuid41261 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2660)
        Format: Sony CV; Duration: 53 minutes; Preservation Note: Video quality is poor. Video lighting is very dark.
      - Video -- 2 of 2 (Box 76, Betacam 481_2348)
    - The New Art Jazz Quartet performance in Charlottesville, Virginia, November, 1969; cuid36860 (Box 56, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1422)
    - Piece for Ulysses Dove and Miscellaneous Trumpet, 1969; cuid36855 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_137)
    - Rehearsal Tape, January, 1969; cuid36858 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1089)
      Featuring Leo Jones (trumpet), Marc Levin (cornet), Marccette Watts (tenor), Marty Cook (trombone), and Dave Chamberlain (flute)
    - String Quartet, March 24, 1969; cuid36859 (Box 11, 1 inch video reel 481_406)
    - "Relay," "Summerdance" Performances by Judith Dunn and Bill Dixon, 1969-1971; cuid36856 (Box 75, Vhs 481_2268)
    - Rehearsal for "Six Pieces" Concert, circa 1970s; cuid36862 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_002)
    - Bill Dixon on Keyboard, 1970; cuid36866
    - Keyboards, Piano and El P, 1970; cuid36867 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_192)
    - Improvisation, circa 1970; cuid36816 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2342)
    - Music Composed by Bill Dixon, circa 1970; cuid36818 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1467)
    - Performance, circa 1970; cuid36817 (Box 62, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2209)
    - Bill Dixon and Steven Horenstein Piano and Flute Performance, May, 1970; cuid36889 (Box 59, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2077)
    - Bill Dixon Solo Piano, May, 1970; cuid36890 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1552)
    - Holly Barrett Solo, Bill Dixon and Steve Horenstein Duet, May, 1970; cuid36887 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_138)
    - October Song, May, 1970; cuid36888 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_416)
    - "Summerdance", August 1, 1970; cuid36891 (Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1090)
    - Steve Horenstein and Bill Dixon, September 23, 1970; cuid36892 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_164)
    - Trumpet and Guitar, December 3, 1970; cuid36893 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_436)
    - Bill Dixon on Piano, circa 1970-1971; cuid36865 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_183)
    - Bill Dixon Trumpet Solos, circa 1970-1971; cuid36879 (Box 58, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1470)
    - Trumpet Solos, circa 1970-1971; cuid36875 (Box 60, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2144)
    - "Fall, 1975", 1970-1975; cuid36863 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_090)
    - "Three Groups of Three" Featuring Sidney Smart, Arthur Brooks, Jay Ash, Henry Letcher, and Holly Schiffer, circa 1970-1975; cuid36874 (Box 63, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2317)
    - Music for Solo Trumpet, circa 1970-1976; cuid36885 (Box 35, Audiocassette 481_1558)
    - Bill Dixon Trumpet Practice, circa 1970-1979; cuid36871 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_445)
    - Flute Duet and Trumpet Duet, circa 1970-1979; cuid36869 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_428)
    - "Letters" Performance Featuring Bill Dixon, Enrico Rava, Scott Guyon, Steve Horenstein, and C. Tronbaum, circa 1970-1979; cuid36870 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_441)
    - Trumpets and Guitar Empty Audio Reel Case, circa 1970-1979; cuid36872 (Box 52)
    - Dance Performance, circa 1970s; cuid36876 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1291)
      Featuring Bill Dixon, Andrew Cyrille, Sam Rivers, Scotty Holt, Arthur Doyle, Judroy Dunn and other dancers
    - Enrico Rava and Bill Dixon Performance, circa 1970s; cuid36877 (Box 98, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1309)
      Featuring Enrico Rava, Bill Dixon, Milford, Letcher, Cook, Moss, and others
      Reel 481_1309 in Box 98 was identified as moldy in September, 2022. This item is currently isolated from other items by housing it in a polyethylene bag with a desiccated board and RH monitor strip. If this strip indicates an RH greater than 50%, the Preservation department should be contacted ASAP. Do not open this packaging without contacting the Preservation Department.
    - "Letters" by Bill Dixon and Henry Letcher, 1970s; cuid36878 (Box 14, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1099)
      Featuring John Hagen, Steve Horenstein, Jay Ash, Jameel Moondol, David Moss, and Henry Letcher
    - Rehearsal, circa 1970s; cuid36880 (Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1437)
    - "Summerdance" Rehearsal, circa 1970-1985; cuid36881 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2462)
    - Compilation Tape -- Untitled, Untitled, "Relay", 1970-1971; cuid36886 (Box 36, Audiocassette 481_1627)
    - Bill Dixon Trumpet, 1970-1975; cuid36894 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_194)
    - Bill Dixon and L. Keck, Wisconsin, 1971; cuid36899
      - Video -- 1 of 5, cuid41240 (Box 13, 1 inch video reel 481_390)
      - Video -- 2 of 5, cuid41241 (Box 5, 1 inch video reel 481_391)
      - Video -- 3 of 5, cuid41242 (Box 1, 1 inch video reel 481_393)
      - Video -- 4 of 5, cuid41243 (Box 8, 1 inch video reel 481_394)
      - Video -- 5 of 5, cuid41244 (Box 7, 1 inch video reel 481_398)
    - Piano and Tenor Steve Horenstein, Bill Dixon, 1971; cuid36895 (Box 50, Quarter inch audio reel 481_187)
    - Piece: Summer 1971, Miscellaneous Ted Joans Music, cuid36904 (Box 43, Audiocassette 481_2482)
    - "S1", July 14, 1971; cuid8726 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_102)
      Possibly a "Summerdance" performance recording or rehearsal.
    - "Summerdance" Prelude, 1971; cuid36896
    - Bill Dixon, L Keck, January 4, 1971; cuid36900 (Box 9, 1 inch video reel 481_403)
    - "The Very Difficult Long Line," "Summerdance", July 18, 1971; cuid8724 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_119)
    - "Cheater" Reel 2, University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, circa 1971-1972; cuid36901 (Box 60, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2157)
    - Orchestra Piece with Voice, Madison, Wisconsin, 1971-1972; cuid36897 (Box 26, Audiocassette 481_632)
    - Orchestra Piece and Two Short Trumpet Pieces, Madison, Wisconsin, 1971-1972; cuid36898 (Box 28, Audiocassette 481_737)
    - Small Orchestra Performance, 1971; cuid36910 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2026)
    - Two Works for Orchestra, 1971-1974; cuid36911 (Box 42, Audiocassette 481_2036)
    - Ensemble Rehearsal -- Arthur Doyle, Steve Horenstein, Scott Guyon, John Buckingham, Bill Dixon, February 4, 1971; cuid36914 (Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1440)
    - Rehearsal, February 9, 1971; cuid36915 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1285)
      Featuring Arthur Doyle and Steve Horenstein (tenor saxophones), Scott Guyon and Bill Dixon (trumpets)
    - Rehearsal, February 10, 1971; cuid36916 (Box 61, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2239)
    - Rehearsal, February 25, 1971; cuid36917 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1091)
      Featuring Steve Horenstein (tenor saxophone), Richard Clay (tuba), John Buckingham (trumpet), Scott Guyon, and Bill Dixon
    - Rehearsal, February 26, 1971; cuid36918 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1098)
      Featuring Steve Horenstein (tenor saxophone), Richard Clay (tenor saxophone), John Buckingham (tuba), Laurence Cook (percussion), and Bill Dixon (trumpet, composer)
    - Rehearsal, March 2, 1971; cuid36919 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_105)
    - Bill Dixon Performance and Talk, March 24, 1971; cuid36920 (Box 19, Audiocassette 481_070)
    - "Piece for Pat Legg" -- Trumpet Convocation, May 13, 1971; cuid36921 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_421)
    - Milford Graves, May 18, 1971; cuid36922 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2665)
      Format: Sony CV; Duration: 66 minutes; Preservation Note: Video quality is poor.
    - S2, July 15, 1971; cuid36923 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_107)
    - July 17, 1971, cuid36925 (Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1446, Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1389)
    - S6, July 18, 1971; cuid36926 (Box 51, Quarter inch audio reel 481_139)
    - Untitled Recording, July 18-20, 1971; cuid36927 (Box 55, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1388, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1387)
    - July 20, 1971, cuid36928 (Box 64, Quarter inch audio reel 481_2062, Box 57, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1447)
    - S14, July 29, 1971; cuid36930 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_108)
    - S13, July 29, 1971; cuid36931 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_109)
    - S16, July 31, 1971; cuid36933 (Box 49, Quarter inch audio reel 481_111)
    - August 4, 1971, cuid36935 (Box 53, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1303, Box 54, Quarter inch audio reel 481_1330)
    - Judith Dunn and Bill Dixon Performance, August 6, 1971; cuid36937
      - Video -- 1 of 2 (Box 76, Betacam 481_2346)
      - Video -- 2 of 2, cuid41264 (Box 80, Half inch video reel 481_2668)
        Format: Sony CV; Duration: 65 minutes; Preservation Note: Video quality is poor.
    - Bill Dixon, September 28, 1971; cuid36938 (Box 11, 1 inch video reel 481_407)
    - Bill Dixon and L. Keck, Wisconsin, September 30, 1971; cuid36939 (Box 9, 1 inch video reel 481_402)
    - Bill Dixon and L. Keck, Wisconsin, October, 1971; cuid36940
      - Video -- 1 of 5, cuid41249 (Box 5, 1 inch video reel 481_395)
      - Video -- 2 of 5, cuid41250 (Box 10, 1 inch video reel 481_401)
      - Video -- 3 of 5, cuid41251 (Box 1, 1 inch video reel 481_006)
      - Video -- 4 of 5, cuid41252 (Box 2, 1 inch video reel 481_007)
      - Video -- 5 of 5, cuid41253 (Box 13, 1 inch video reel 481_400)
    - "Summerdance" Performances, July-August, 1971; cuid36936 (Box 52, Quarter inch audio reel 481_422)
      Duration: 25 minutes; Preservation note: Discussion between the musical interludes is at a very low volume